<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF8'?>
<data>
  <corpus>
    <news>
      <value name="head">Brain Disconnects During Sleep</value>
      <value name="text">Scientists may have gained an important insight into the age-old mystery of why consciousness fades as we nod off to sleep.
          Lines of communication between various parts of cerebral cortex - which buzz with activity during wakefulness - break down during slumber, researchers report today in Science.
          Early neuroscientists assumed that consciousness wanes during sleep because the cortex simply shuts off.
          But electroencephalography (EEG) and other modern methods have since ruled out that explanation, showing that the electrical chatter and metabolism of neurons in the cortex continues unabated during sleep.
          That left neuroscientists with a puzzle: If the brain is still active, why does consciousness wane?
          Giulio Tononi of the University of Wisconsin, Madison, suspected that a communication breakdown might be the reason.
          Tononi has spent years developing a theory that equates consciousness with the integration of information.
          Communication between regions of the cortex might be one sign of this integration - and of consciousness, Tononi says.
          To test that idea, he and his team recorded electrical activity in the brains of six sleepy volunteers using high density EEG.
          Before the subjects nodded off, the researchers stimulated a small patch of right frontal cortex with transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS), a method that uses magnetic pulses to induce an electrical current inside the head.
          When the subjects were awake, TMS elicited waves of neural activity that spread through neighboring areas of right frontal and parietal cortex and to corresponding regions on the left side of the brain.
          During non-rapid eye movement (non-REM) sleep, the same TMS stimulus only elicited neural activity at the site of stimulation.
          Tononi says the findings suggest that different areas of cortex do indeed stop talking to each other during non-REM sleep - a stage in which people often report little or no conscious experience on waking.
          An important follow-up, he says, will be to repeat the experiments during late-night REM sleep, when people often report consciouslike experiences in the form of dreams.
          'We would predict a pattern which is much more similar to wakefulness,' he says.
          The research 'definitely tells us something about sleep and may have important implications for understanding the neural correlates of consciousness,' says Christof Koch, a cognitive neuroscientist at the California Institute of Technology in Pasadena.</value>
    </news>
    <news>
      <value name="head">New Portuguese skull may be an early relative of Neandertals</value>
      <value name="text">Half a million years ago, several different members of our genus, Homo, had spread throughout Europe and Asia, where some would eventually evolve into Neandertals.
          But which ones has been the subject of intense debate.
          A newly discovered partial skull is offering another clue to help solve the mystery of the ancestry of Neandertals.
          Found in 2014 in the Gruta da Aroeira cave in central Portugal with ancient stone hand axes, the skull (3D reconstruction pictured) is firmly dated to 400,000 years old and an archaic member of our genus, according to a study published today in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences.
          The skull shows a new mix of features not seen before in fossil humans-it has traits that link it to Neandertals, such as a fused brow ridge, as well as some primitive traits that resemble other extinct fossils in Europe.
          This new combination of features on a well-dated skull may help researchers sort out how different fossils in Europe are related to each other-and which ones eventually evolved into Neandertals.</value>
    </news>
    <news>
      <value name="head">Living by the coast could improve mental health</value>
      <value name="text">People who live close to the sea have better mental health than those who live further away, regardless of their household income, a new study suggests.
          According to scientists, living near the sea could support better mental health in England's poorest communities.
          Researchers from the University of Exeter used survey data from 25,963 respondents in their investigations into the wellbeing effects of being by the coast.
          After taking other related factors into account, they found that living in large towns and cities near the coastline is linked with better mental health for those in the lowest earning households.
          The research suggests those who live less than a kilometre from the coast are around 22 per cent less likely to have symptoms of a mental health disorder than those who live 50km or more away.
          Those from low income households less than a kilometre from the coast are around 40 per cent less likely to have symptoms, compared to those earning the same amount living more than 50km away.
          Around one in six adults in England suffer from mental health disorders such as anxiety and depression, and these are far more likely in people from poorer backgrounds.
          Published in the Health and Place journal, the findings suggest access to the coast could help to reduce these health inequalities in towns and cities close to the sea.
          The research used data from the Health Survey for England and compared people's health to their proximity to the coast.
          Researchers say their findings add to the growing evidence that access to blue spaces-particularly coastal environments-might improve health and wellbeing.
          Dr Jo Garrett, who led the study, said: 'Our research suggests, for the first time, that people in poorer households living close to the coast experience fewer symptoms of mental health disorders.
          When it comes to mental health, this 'protective' zone could play a useful role in helping to level the playing field between those on high and low income.'
          Dr Mathew White, environmental psychologist at the University of Exeter, said: 'This kind of research into blue health is vital to convincing governments to protect, create and encourage the use of coastal spaces.
          'We need to help policy makers understand how to maximise the wellbeing benefits of 'blue' spaces in towns and cities and ensure that access is fair and inclusive for everyone, while not damaging our fragile coastal environments.'</value>
    </news>
    <news>
      <value name="head">Did you knowingly commit a crime? Brain scans could tell</value>
      <value name="text">The number of years someone spends behind bars can hinge on whether they were clearly aware that they were committing a crime.
          But how is a judge or jury to know for sure?
          A new study suggests brain scans can distinguish between hardcore criminal intent and simple reckless behavior, but the approach is far from being ready for the courtroom.
          The study is unusual because it looks directly at the brains of people while they are engaged in illicit activity, says Liane Young, a Boston College psychologist who was not involved in the work.
          Earlier research, including work by her, has instead generally looked at the brains of people only observing immoral activity.
          Researchers led by Read Montague, a neuroscientist at Virginia Tech Carilion Research Insitute in Roanoke and at University College London,  used functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI), which can measure brain activity based on blood flow.
          They analyzed the brains of 40 people-a mix of men and women mostly in their 20s and 30s-as they went through scenarios that simulated trying to smuggle something through a security checkpoint.
          In some cases, the people knew for certain they had contraband in a suitcase.
          In other cases, they chose from between two and five suitcases, with only one containing contraband (and thus they weren't sure they were carrying contraband).
          The risk of getting caught also varied based on how many of the 10 security checkpoints had a guard stationed there.
          The results showed distinctive patterns of brain activity for when the person knew for certain the suitcase had contraband and when they only knew there was a chance of it, the team reports today in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences.
          But there was an unexpected twist.
          Those differing brain patterns only showed up when people were first shown how many security checkpoints were guarded, and then offered the suitcases.
          In that case, a computer analysis of the fMRI images correctly classified people as knowing or reckless between 71% and 80% of the time.
          Montague isn't sure why the results hinged on the order in which the scenario unfolded.
          It's possible there is some threshold for the amount of information the brain needed before a distinctive thought process connected to recklessness kicked in, he says.
          In the laboratory, he says, perhaps the information about both the risk of grabbing a 'hot' suitcase and of encountering a security guard 'had to be all on board before we could see this difference.'
          'I see this as a proof of principle that raises more questions than it answers,' says Montague, who notes that his team repeated the experiment several times with the same results.
          The lawyers working on the study recoiled at the idea that the results depended on the sequencing of the events, because people were engaged in risky behavior no matter the order.
          'I'm a scientist, so I was like, 'This is the most interesting part of what we've found.
          We don't know what to do with this,'' Montague says.
          But another researcher who has used brain imaging to study criminal behavior questioned whether the differences found in the study really revealed a meaningful difference between the two mental states.
          Ruben Gur, a psychologist and director of the Brain Behavior Laboratory at the University of Pennsylvania's medical school, says that with just 40 participants, a study may not be able to account for all the variables at play in brain scans.
          'To me, it proves that when you apply a statistical method on small samples you come up with interesting results, and some that make less sense.'
          Study author Gideon Yaffe, a philosopher at Yale Law School, notes there are some limitations of the research.
          It's not known whether the different brain patterns are confined to this very specific scenario, or would apply more broadly to other situations outside the lab, he says.
          And he cautions that it's a very big leap from there to visions of 'evil intent detectors' scanning people's brains.
          'It was so hard to do this modest thing that it feels very, very far away to be able to do something as grand as that.'
          A more relevant scenario might be looking at whether the brains of people with certain conditions, such as drug addiction, process risk differently.
          That research, Yaffe says, might be introduced in court as people wrestle with how much someone really knew as they committed a crime.</value>
    </news>
    <news>
      <value name="head">Computer learns to detect skin cancer more accurately than doctors</value>
      <value name="text">A computer was better than human dermatologists at detecting skin cancer in a study that pitted people against machines in the quest for better, faster diagnostics, researchers said on Tuesday.
          A team from Germany, the United States and France taught an artificial intelligence system to distinguish dangerous skin lesions from benign ones, showing it more than 100,000 images.
          The machine - a deep learning convolutional neural network or CNN - was then tested against 58 dermatologists from 17 countries, shown photos of malignant melanomas and benign moles.
          Just over half the dermatologists were at expert level with more than five years of experience, 19% had between two and five years' experience, and 29% were beginners with less than two years under their belt.
          'Most dermatologists were outperformed by the CNN, the research team wrote in a paper published in the journal Annals of Oncology.
          On average,human dermatologists accurately detected 86.6% of skin cancers from the images, compared to 95% for the CNN.
          'The CNN missed fewer melanomas, meaning it had a higher sensitivity than the dermatologists,' the study's first author Holger Haenssle of the University of Heidelberg said in a statement.
          It also 'misdiagnosed fewer benign moles as malignant melanoma ... this would result in less unnecessary surgery.'
          The dermatologists' performance improved when they were given more information of the patients and their skin lesions.
          The team said AI may be a useful tool for faster, easier diagnosis of skin cancer, allowing surgical removal before it spreads.
          There are about 232,000 new cases of melanoma, and 55,500 deaths, in the world each year, they added.
          Melanoma in some parts of the body, such as the fingers, toes and scalp, are difficult to image, and AI may have difficulty recognising atypical lesions or ones that patients themselves are unaware of.
          Currently, there is no substitute for a thorough clinical examination,' experts Victoria Mar from Monash University in Melbourne and Peter Soyer of the University of Queensland wrote in an editorial published with the study.</value>
    </news>
    <news>
      <value name="head">US economic growth stronger than expected despite weak demand</value>
      <value name="text">US economic growth surged in the first three months of the year to 3.2% as the threat of a trade war with China forced businesses to stockpile at the fastest rate since 2015.
          Figures from the Department of Commerce showed that a jump in hoarding raw materials and finished goods and an increase in government investment overcame weak consumer spending, a drop in housebuilding and low business investment to send GDP growth well ahead of the 2.2% in the last quarter of 2018.
          Exports, which have proved volatile in recent quarters in response to threats of a trade war between the US and China, surged and imports declined to add 1.03 percentage points to GDP after being neutral in the fourth quarter.
          The improvement dispelled concerns the US economy was heading into recession as early as the summer, as some analysts had feared,after a slowdown last year.
          But analysts said the Federal Reserve, which has put interest rate hikes on hold, was unlikely to view the figures as the beginning of an economic boom and reverse its current policy.
          In January, the US central bank suspended its three-year push to tighten monetary policy, saying it would pause further rate hikes this year. The Fed increased borrowing costs four times to a range of 2.25 to 2.5% in 2018, well above the level of base rates for most other major economies.
          The central bank is more likely to focus on a measure of domestic demand, which increased by only 1.3%, the slowest since the second quarter of 2013, after increasing by 2.6% in the last quarter.
          Growth in consumer spending, which accounts for more than two-thirds of US economic activity, was also weak, growing by just 1.2% from the previous 2.5%. Business investment slowed sharply, rising at only at a 0.2% rate, the slowest since the third quarter of 2016.
          Reports from China show that the world's second largest economy has arrested last year's decline, though many analysts believe the better outlook will prove temporary and growth will be lower this year than in 2018.
          European manufacturing has slumped in recent months and Japanese output has slowed, marking the US out as the only major economy maintaining high levels of output growth.
          The effect of stockpiling in the US has also buoyed activity in the UK, where the uncertainty over Brexit negotiations has unnerved businesses and encouraged them to hoard raw materials.
          In April, British factories have stockpiled at the fastest pace since records began in the 1950s amid reports they were increasingly downbeat about their prospects.
          A survey by the Confederation of British Industry found expectations for export orders in the next three months fell to their lowest level since mid-2009.</value>
    </news>
    <news>
      <value name="head">Microsoft becomes third listed US firm to be valued at $1tn</value>
      <value name="text">Microsoft has become the third publicly listed US company, after Apple and Amazon, to boast a market value of more than $1tn after bumper quarterly results boosted its share price.
          The company beat sales and profits expectations in the three months to 31 March, thanks in part to its cloud computing business, which signed up major corporate clients over the period.
          Microsoft shares rose as much as 5% in early trading on Thursday, briefly pushing its market value above $1tn for the first time before dipping back below again when the shares price gain eased.
          It was the latest tech firm to join the prestigious club, after rival Apple and then Amazon topped the $1tn mark last year.
          Since then, the shares of both companies have fallen back and Microsoft now has the biggest market capitalisation of any US stock market listed company.
          Shares in Facebook were also trading higher, up 6%, after it easily beat forecasts with a 26% jump in quarterly revenues to more than $15bn and an 8% rise in active users.
          The better-than-expected results from Microsoft and Facebook helped to push the tech-focused Nasdaq share index in New York to over 8,118 points at its close.
          The boost for Microsoft came after it reported a 14% increase in revenue in its third quarter to $30.6bn. Net income rose 19% to $8.8bn. Revenues in its cloud computing division jumped 14%, with US grocery firm Kroger and Walgreens Boots Alliance among the big client wins.
          Satya Nadella, the chief executive of Microsoft, said: 'Leading organisations of every size in every industry trust the Microsoft cloud. We are accelerating our innovation across the cloud and edge so our customers can build the digital capability increasingly required to compete and grow.'
          Shares in Microsoft were up 3.4% at $129 at close of trading in New York, giving it a market value of about $995bn. Apple is worth around $970bn and Amazon is close behind at $940bn.
          Brad Reback of stockbrokers Stifel said Microsoft has a bright future: 'We continue to believe the shift to the cloud will be additive to Microsoft given a broader portfolio of products with deeper functionality as well as Microsoft's ability to enter new categories where it did not compete previously.'
          Stifel has raised its price target for Microsoft to $150 from $130.
          Cloud is clearly the way forward for Microsoft and demand for these services is expected to remain strong,' said Jasper Lawler, the head of research at London Capital Group.</value>
    </news>
    <news>
      <value name="head">Apple's Siri is a better rapper than you</value>
      <value name="text">Siri, Apple's voice-controlled virtual assistant, is not just useful for hands-free texting, dictation and pizza place recommendations - it turns out she is also a skilled rapper.
          Last month, Judith Newman wrote in the New York Times how Siri had befriended her autistic son, and now it seems that Siri's talents go even further.
          London-based producers Skeewiff, aka Alex Rizzo and Elliot Ireland, have uploaded a remix of Young MC's Know How that features Siri.
          Siri's flow is reminiscent of Nicki Minaj's best work on Monster; she has cadence just as smooth as Angel Haze; and a potty mouth worthy of Azealia Banks.
          As well as name-checking Spotify and Google, Siri's enunciation of Young's rapid-fire lyrics are near-perfect, rapping: I'm tough like a bone / sly like Stallone / rocking and clocking on the microphone / smooth like a mirror / in hearts I strike terror / rhymes like runs / and rhymes with no errors.
          The producers who worked with Siri said they were thrilled with her performance.
          Rizzo told the Guardian how the collaboration came about: She's set to British Female.
          I asked her to dial up the lyrics of one of my favourite boasting hip hop tracks of all time, Young MC's Know How.
          When I asked her to read them out, well that was when the real ROFL-ing started.
          Tears and everything. Something about that posh English, mechanical accent busting rhymes was just irresistible.
          At that moment I knew what needed to be done, the rest was just recording, replaying and a whole lot of editing.'
          This is not the first time Siri has taken to the mic though.
          She has previously covered Eminem's Lose Yourself (not a great effort), and, to better effect, Notorious BIG's Hypnotize.
          X Factor, watch out.</value>
    </news>
    <news>
      <value name="head">Netflix viewers like comedy for breakfast and drama at lunch</value>
      <value name="text">Netflix viewers prefer a diet of comedy at breakfast, a portion of drama on their lunch break and a midnight snack of documentaries.
          Netflix, which has more than 100 million subscribers worldwide, said analysis of viewing data found that users of its service were keen to start the day with a laugh by watching comedies such as , Fuller House and.
          At 6am members are 34% more likely to watch a comedy than at any other time of the day, the data, gathered from users across 22 countries, shows.
          Sneaking in an episode of a drama at lunchtime has emerged as a popular pastime with shows in the genre, such as Mad Men, Bloodline or Orange is the New Black, accounting for 47% of all viewing between noon and 2pm.
          Evening viewing is peppered with a range of usual suspects, including Breaking Bad and Stranger Things, as viewership of the thriller genre increases by more than a quarter by 9pm.
          It is back to comedies just before lights out with It's Always Sunny in Philadelphia, Master of None and BoJack Horseman taking over at 11pm.
          For night owls - 15% of Netflix viewing occurs between midnight and 6am - documentaries are popular.
          In that period there is a 24% surge in the viewing of documentaries such as Making a Murderer and Planet Earth.
          Netflix says its business model, which enables viewers to binge-watch entire series in one go, counter to the traditional TV model, has resulted in marked changes in the kind of shows being watched.
          'For years our lives had to fit around television, now it's the other way round,' said Cindy Holland, the vice-president of original content at Netflix.
          'We've given consumers control and it's interesting to see the behaviours that emerge when viewers aren't tied to a schedule.'
          Netflix said the trend suggests that the traditional TV viewing pattern - of breakfast news shows followed by a lighter schedule during the day and lights off by midnight - no longer applies.
          'Gone are the days of every household waking up to the same breakfast TV programming on their screens,' the company said.
          'When viewing schedules are set by people and not programmers, lunchtime becomes no bingeing exception.'
          Netflix analysed six months of streaming data from the 22 countries, including the UK, Argentina, Brazil, India, New Zealand and the US.</value>
    </news>
    <news>
      <value name="head">Loneliness May Make Quitting Smoking Even Tougher</value>
      <value name="text">Being lonely may make it harder to quit smoking, a new British study suggests.
          Using genetic and survey data from hundreds of thousands of people, researchers found that loneliness makes it more likely that someone will smoke.
          This type of analysis is called Mendelian randomization.
          'This method has never been applied to this question before and so the results are novel, but also tentative,' said co-lead author Robyn Wootton, a senior research associate at the University of Bristol in the United Kingdom.
          'We found evidence to suggest that loneliness leads to increased smoking, with people more likely to start smoking, to smoke more cigarettes and to be less likely to quit,' Wootton said in a university news release.
          These data mesh with an observation that during the coronavirus pandemic, more British people are smoking.
          Senior study author Jorien Treur said, 'Our finding that smoking may also lead to more loneliness is tentative, but it is in line with other recent studies that identified smoking as a risk factor for poor mental health.
          A potential mechanism for this relationship is that nicotine from cigarette smoke interferes with neurotransmitters such as dopamine in the brain.'
          Treur is a visiting research associate from Amsterdam UMC.
          The researchers also looked for a connection between loneliness and drinking but found none.
          Still, if loneliness causes people to smoke, it is important to alert smoking cessation services so they can add this factor as they help people to quit, the study authors said.
          The report was published June 16 in the journal Addiction.</value>
    </news>
  </corpus>
</data>
